<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sine's Site</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sine's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 20:14:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ssine.ink/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Layout Animation: FLIP and Reparenting</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/layout-animation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 20:14:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/layout-animation/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
When I was developing Kiwi recently, I encountered some problems with the front-end layout animation. It is quite interesting to study it in depth. The following two points are related to the animation transition when the layout changes.
The first is when an item displayed in the content bar changes, just put the new item to the end when adding, but if the previous item is removed, the item below will slide up, as shown in the following figure:</description></item><item><title>Personal Automation System and Information Dashboard</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/personal-automation-n-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:51:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/personal-automation-n-dashboard/</guid><description>Note: This article is mainly translated by Google translator, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. For a while, I paid more attention to digital health and automation, so I tossed a wave of related things and engaged in data storage and Kanban. Recalling that the entire process feels like a micro data warehouse, you need to obtain the data source yourself, design the storage</description></item><item><title>Set Up and Application of HPE MicroServer</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/homeserver/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 01:05:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/homeserver/</guid><description>Note: This article is mainly translated by Google translator, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
I bought HPE MicroServer Gen 10 Plus a few months ago, and it has been running stably since it was configured. Let’s talk about the configuration and application of the home server. Buying a host and turning it on at home throughout the year will be specially used as a server.</description></item><item><title>Soft routing and home network configuration</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/soft-router/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 23:20:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/soft-router/</guid><description>Note: This article is mainly translated by Google translator, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
I usually like to toss something at home. For many services, soft routing is an infrastructure. The concept of soft routing is opposite to hard routing. Hard routing refers to a device that forwards network packets by proprietary hardware, while soft routing is a device that forwards network packets by a general-purpose computer through software.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi for temperature and humidity reporting and infrared control</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/rpi-thermometer-and-ir/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:48:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/rpi-thermometer-and-ir/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. For a while, I was tossing around collecting various data, one of which was the temperature and humidity of the room. I bought a humidifier at the beginning, but I don’t know how it works, so I bought a Xiaomi thermometer and hygrometer. Unexpectedly, exporting data from this</description></item><item><title>Self-hosted chat server, chatbot and multi-platform bridging</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/matrix-bot-and-bridges/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:36:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/matrix-bot-and-bridges/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. Preface Use open source solutions to build your own chat server, end-to-end encryption, no annoying EULA, control data yourself, you can form a federation with other servers, and even chat with other chat software&amp;rsquo;s individuals and groups through bridges-it seems It&amp;rsquo;s perfect. Of course, the entire system needs a little time to</description></item><item><title>Building a Jupyter Lab Container with Multiple Kernels</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/versatile-jupyter-lab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:08:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/versatile-jupyter-lab/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Usually there are some small ideas that need to be tested. For example, to see if TypeScript can support this syntax, use Python to do two questions and quickly process some files. At this time, it is more cumbersome to open an editor to write a script and then run it. Putting the environment of various languages on the machine is also messy and not portable.</description></item><item><title>Win10 Multi-monitor DPI Adjustment</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/win10-dual-screen-resolution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 18:21:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/win10-dual-screen-resolution/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Win10 currently has poor support for multiple different dpi displays. In the display settings, the canvas size of the display is determined by the resolution of the display rather than the physical size of the display. This leads to annoying misalignment when a window spans different monitors, and the mouse cannot be aligned when the mouse is moved across different monitors.</description></item><item><title>Use Caddy to enable HTTPS on ports other than 443</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/caddy-non-443-port-https/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 21:18:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/caddy-non-443-port-https/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Recently I started with HPE ProLiant MicroServer Gen10 Plus and used it as a home server to avoid long-term rental of cloud servers. Although home servers have obvious advantages in cost performance compared with cloud servers, they lack an important content of cloud services: fixed public IP. We usually use the public IP in order to be able to access the server anytime and anywhere, and this requirement can also be achieved through DDNS, but access requires a domain name instead of a bare IP.</description></item><item><title>Critical Section in Asynchronous Environment</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/critical-section-in-async-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 21:42:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/critical-section-in-async-environment/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Recently, I encountered an interesting problem when writing the check-in bot in the quiz group, so let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it.
After a punch-in dialogue is completed, the program needs to write the data into the file, and then it will call the NodeJS API (JavaScript):
class XXX { async saveData() { await fs.</description></item><item><title>Tips on Typesetting in Microsoft Word</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/office-word-tips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 18:22:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/office-word-tips/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. The final paper is completed in Word, here is a summary of how I used Word to achieve some relatively complex typesetting requirements. Automatic numbering and references Chapter title First look at the title requirements: First level heading: bold number three, bold Secondary heading: bold number four, bold Level three headings and</description></item><item><title>Trading Intro</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/trading-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:04:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/trading-introduction/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. stock Dutch East India Company In the 17th century, with the development of navigation technology, many European countries, including the Netherlands, began large-scale colonial expansion. Spices in Europe were very scarce at that time, and trading in spices with Asia could earn dozens of times more profit. Stimulated by high profits, various</description></item><item><title>WeChat History Extraction</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/wechat-data-decryption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:17:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/wechat-data-decryption/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Recently, I need to share some chat records with others. Because the large amount of screenshots is too troublesome, I want to take the WeChat data directly and back it up by the way. Follow the common process, take the EnMicroMsg.db file, find the password, and export. However, when the database password was obtained, the mobile phone imei used to register WeChat was untestable, and the current mobile phone failed.</description></item><item><title>My College Life</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/my-college-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/my-college-life/</guid><description>Note: This passage is mainly translated by Google translator, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
After leaving MSRA a few weeks ago, I started to do nothing, sleep late, play games, and are reluctant to accept the fact that I am about to start applying for a school. After the senior year, I gradually fell out of school. I only had one class per week.</description></item><item><title>Super Mario Maker 2: Music Level</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/smm2-music-course/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/smm2-music-course/</guid><description>I bought switch for Super Mario Maker2, and have been playing in multiplayer and durance mode after I&amp;rsquo;ve cleared story mode. The idea of making music levels strikes me and I&amp;rsquo;ve started investigation. For thoese who doesn;t know music levels, see the video: https://www.bilibili.com/video/av65739781 . The Mechanism First of all, explain the mechanism of the music map in the game, there are three points: The system only loads blocks near</description></item><item><title>Setup of Personal Non-linear Notebook TiddlyWiki Server</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/tiddlywiki-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/tiddlywiki-setup/</guid><description>TiddlyWiki TiddlyWiki is a note-taking app for managing complex information. It has two features that I really like:
Philosophy of Tiddlers I think people have two purposes for taking notes. One is to deepen the understanding of knowledge by means of the output process of taking notes, and the other is to facilitate reuse of this knowledge in the future. The former is a temporary role, but the notes for this purpose need not be saved, while the latter is very important, and a relatively complete form is needed to organize the knowledge for later reference.</description></item><item><title>Minecraft Bedrock Edition Mod Description</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/mcbe-mods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/mcbe-mods/</guid><description>After Microsoft acquired Minecraft, it rewrote the game in C++, which brought a bright future to MCs with confusing code, frequent bugs, and difficult mod development, and called this high-performance and stable version a bedrock version. The pros and cons of the bedrock version 1Bedrock version with respect to the Java version of it is there are too many improvements, Java version of the shortcomings detailed in Minecraft game code</description></item><item><title>DBMS Implementation</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/dbms-implementation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/dbms-implementation/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. Overview I want to do a database management system DBMS in the elementary school next semester, because I think it is very interesting, so I plan to write it in advance. some thoughts First, I want to try the development model of Typescript + Electron. Javascript is almost my favorite programming language</description></item><item><title>Life Calendar</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/life-calendar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/life-calendar/</guid><description>Life Calendar I have spent some time thinking about life recently. I feel that there are some things in the past. If I forget it, I will never find it again. Many events are not a big deal, and no one remembers for me. If I even forget, what are the meanings of those things? So I want to do something, save and clearly show what happened in the past</description></item><item><title>'Ph.D. Grind' Reflection</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/phd-grind-reflection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/phd-grind-reflection/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. There is still no clear plan for my future. There are many ways to go in the future. Beiyou Zhibo, foreign school insurance research, overseas study and study/reading blogs must be slowly understood. At the same time, you need to figure out what you want, but these also require more experience to</description></item><item><title>MS Student Camp 2018</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/ms-camp-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/ms-camp-2018/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Microsoft’s student summer camps have been held for 18 consecutive years. Although there are some colors to promote Microsoft’s technology, they are also very sentimental.
Summer camp is not a devil activity with the first goal of transferring knowledge, so just have a good time. The most interesting event for hackers isGolden dot game: Submit two numbers for each group, see the rest of the rulesOriginal URL.</description></item><item><title>Cambridge Travel Notes</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/cambridge-travel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/cambridge-travel/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. A two-week summer course at Cambridge University from 7.29-8.12. Funded by the School of Computer Science and undertaken by the CUDC UK-China Development Center. Before departure This summer class was organized by the School of Computer Science, and the selection of freshman to junior year in the college was relatively stable. It</description></item><item><title>Bomb Lab</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/bomb-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/bomb-lab/</guid><description>This is the fourth experiment of assembly language. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to use the well-known bomb lab on CSAPP. It is also very powerful.
Turn the bomb into a &amp;ldquo;dumb bomb&amp;rdquo; As a perfectionist of the glass heart, naturally, I don&amp;rsquo;t want my own explosive record to be registered, so I have to find a way to debug the bomb locally. Fortunately, both sides are x86, at least binary files can run.</description></item><item><title>Windows Virtual Memory Intro</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/windows-virtual-memory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/windows-virtual-memory/</guid><description>Note: This passage is mainly translated by Google translator, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible. Virtual memory provides a logical view of memory, it does not correspond to the layout of physical memory. During operation, the memory manager maps virtual addresses to physical addresses with the help of hardware support. Each process has its own virtual address space, and it will feel that it</description></item><item><title>Reader-Writer Problem</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/reader-writer-problem/reader-writer-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/reader-writer-problem/reader-writer-problem/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
This is an experiment in the operating system class, using the semaphore mechanism to realize the reader-writer problem. Use n threads to represent n readers and writers.
Operational restrictions for reader-writer problems:
Write-write mutual exclusion Read-write mutual exclusion Read-read allowed Additional restrictions for readers priority: If a reader is already reading when another reader is applying for a read operation, the reader can directly start the read operation.</description></item><item><title>Automated Image Script</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/auto-image-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/auto-image-script/</guid><description>A script written at any time for the convenience of taking notes and/or removing white background and uploading images to the OSS service.
When I recently wrote notes, I encountered the problem of putting the handwritten/screen content on the paper on the webpage. This is a manual solution: scan the Evernote document, save it to the computer, download it on the computer, PS Remove the white background, upload it to OSS, get the image link, and insert it into the note.</description></item><item><title>CHIP-8 Emulator</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/chip8-emulator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/chip8-emulator/</guid><description>A project from the design of computer composition principles. Introduction Why do it The experimental class of computer composition principle should write a Virtual Machine in a high-level language. The first step is to hand over the design report. In the past few days, I have been thinking about what kind of VM to do after thinking about it. Software re-engineering the Proteus CPU of the last semester is too</description></item><item><title>2017 Events</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/2017-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/2017-things/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Record what I have done this year, although I have almost forgot it, recalling it according to the notes and calendar. It feels like another year has been wasted. In fact, there are many things that have happened and done, but when it comes to major events, they are not very good.</description></item><item><title>My First MCM</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/my-first-mcm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/my-first-mcm/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
From February 9th to 13th, 2018, I participated in the first mathematics modeling competition with very insufficient preparation. In order to better communicate with teammates, I rented a homestay in Tianjin to play games. On the last day of the 13th, I had a heavy meeting with the high school class (Can Nian).</description></item><item><title>MCM Notes</title><link>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/mcm-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssine.ink/en/posts/mcm-notes/</guid><description>Note: This article is automatically translated, please turn to the Chinese version for more accurate expression if possible.
Make a simple record of MCM in nine days&amp;hellip;
After being familiar with the competition, it is roughly divided into the parts of finding resources, learning, and reading papers, which are not completely executed in sequence.
Find resources First understand the basic information,Official website. It is estimated that there are too many Chinese people participating, even Tips has a Chinese version, you must watch it.</description></item></channel></rss>